Bruno P. Kinoshita

(021) 104 2131 • ☑ kinow@apache.org • ❷ https://kinoshita.eti.br
 in brunopkinoshita • ¥ kinow • ♠ kinow
 Brazilian-New Zealander, married, 36 years old, non-smoker

In the past seventeen years have worked in different industries including telecommunications, banking, credit, retail, insurance, research, government, and start-ups. Occupied different positions such as programmer, quality engineer, devops, architect, full stack developer, big data engineer, and frontend developer.

I am fluent in English and Portuguese. I have an intermediate level of Spanish, and basic of Japanese and French. Attended Te Reo Maori beginner classes to learn basic vocabulary and pronunciation.

Skills

Languages Java, Python, PHP, R, C/C++, CSS, HTML, JavaScript, Shell, Perl, SQL Frameworks Node.js, NumPy, Pandas, Spark, Spring, SpringBoot, Struts, Hadoop, Tornado,

Laravel

Systems Linux, OSX, Windows

Other Open Source, GIS, Semantic Web, Linked Data, Natural Language Processing

Achievements

o GSoC Mentor, Jenkins Machine Learning Plug-in
March 2020, to September 2020
o Invited to become an Apache Software Foundation Member
March 2018
o Spirit of GovHack for amazing team work

O NIWA Proactive Communicator

March 2020, to September 2020
February 2016

Education

o BSc Information Systems, Mackenzie University

August 2003 - July 2007

Training

o Privacy 101 - the Office of the Privacy Commissioner's online eLearning module. Privacy Com	nmissioner	
Te Mana Matapono Matatapu. Online.	2021	
o Intro to Vue.js, Real World Vue.js, Advanced Components, Next-Level Vue, Mastering Vue.	ex, Vue 3	
Composition API, From Vue 2 to Vue 3, Vue $3 + Typescript$. Vue Mastery. Online.	2020	
o Building Web Applications in R with Shiny. DataCamp. Online.	2018	
o OWASP NZ Day Advanced Web Hacking and Secure Coding. University of Auckland. Auckl	and, New	
Zealand.	2017	
o AWS Concepts. Linux Academy. Online.	2016	
o Basics of Geographic Coordinate Systems, Telling Your Story With Esri Story Maps, Achieving Interoper-		

o Basics of Geographic Coordinate Systems,	Telling Your Story With Esri Story Maps,	Achieving Interoper-
ability Using ArcGIS and OGC Standards	. Esri. Auckland, New Zealand.	2016

o OWASP New Zealand day training. OWASP. Auckland, New Zealand. 2016

o Web Development with Servlets and JSP. Sun Microsystems. Sao Paulo, Brazil. 2007

o COBIT and Sarbanes-Oxley. Claro. Sao Paulo, Brazil. 2006

Experience

Research Software Engineer, NIWA

October 2018 – Today

- Working remotely from Auckland on Cylc using Python Tornado and JavaScript Vue.js.

Java Engineer, NIWA

Jun 2017 - Sep 2018

- Java **JEE** development for EcoConnect.

o Full Stack Software Developer, Spark Ventures

Oct 2016 - Jun 2017

- AWS development, build systems, and Java development using SpringBoot.

Software Developer / Operations, NIWA

Apr 2015 - Sep 2016

- Configuration management, automation, Java development, CI and DevOps pipelines.

o **Senior Big Data Engineer**, Boa Vista Servicos (Equifax)

Jun 2014 - Mar 2015

- Impala, HDFS, **Hadoop**. Cobol and Java development. Creation of business cases for execute and management teams.

o Senior Software Architect, Tokio Marine

Jan 2013 - May 2014

 ActiveMQ cluster, internal workshops and trainings, internal web services, SSO, integration of new Portal with Liferay. Company-wide KPI monitoring implementation.

o Senior Infrastructure Engineer, Tokio Marine

Oct 2012 - Dec 2013

Automation with Jenkins and Puppet.

o Senior Software Engineer, Tokio Marine

Oct 2011 - Sep 2012

- Java web development with Servlets, Portlets, and **LifeRay** modules. SSO with **OpenAM**, QA environment with **Jenkins**, Ivy, and other tools.

Senior System Analyst, Lojas Riachuelo

Jul 2011 - Sep 2011

- Java Swing development for retail POS system.

o Senior Software Quality Engineer, Vivo (Telefonica)

Jan 2010 - Jun 2011

CRM development with Java and GWT. QA pipeline set up with Hudson, Sonar, Testlink, FishEye, and JIRA.

o Senior Software Engineer, Nossa Caixa Bank

Apr 2008 – Dec 2009

 - .NET C# and Java support development. Integration with Mainframes using Cobol, MQSeries, DirectConnect, Uniface, and Java in Z/OS Linux.

o Junior System Analyst, Claro

Jun 2007 – Mar 2008

- Java web development and J2EE using Servlets, EJBs, JMS.

o Junior System Technician, Claro

Jan 2006 - May 2007

- **Java Swing** and J2EE.

o Value Added Services intern, Claro

Jul 2004 - Dec 2005

- VAS middleware systems, billing integration, Java development on HP-UX and Solaris.

Certifications

o gvSIG User Certificate	2018
o Professional Scrum Master I (scrum.org)	2011
o ISTQB CTFL Certified Tester	2010
o SCWCD Sun Certified Web Component Developer	2009